<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jaya Mishra</title>
    <description>Doctor. Poetess. Writer.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 22:19:56 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 22:19:56 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.0</generator>
    
      
        <item>
          
            <title>A Letter to Ms. Green</title>
          
          <author>mail@jayamishra.com (Jaya Mishra)</author>
          <description>
            &lt;p&gt;Dear Ms Green,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for calling me the other day. Although brief, the last conversation we had over the dead telephone was the most real conversation I have had in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’re doing as well as you said you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something strange happened the other day, I could use the word “abhorrent” but not sure if it would suffice. I haven’t still figured out how to feel about the whole thing. If it was any other day, I would have said that I was angry, disgusted, ashamed, or scared even; but the truth is, my feelings about it are deeper than that. And the exact way I feel about it is still a bit confusing to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was exactly two days ago, my refrigerator had been empty for weeks and I had been postponing the trip to grocery shopping primarily because of my laziness, but also due to the constant exhaustive state I have lately been in. But I had run out of beer, so the grocery shopping had become indispensable at this point. I would describe to you my clothing and walk to the mall, but have decided that such information is neither necessary nor relevant to what happened next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my walk back to my apartment with both my hands occupied with huge plastic bags I was carrying from the mall, a car with tainted windows slowed down and the door to the back seats opened while parallel to me. Two men sitting with their pants down at their ankles and rubbing their cocks looked directly at my face. I looked at them, then at their hands, then at their cocks, back to their face – too confused to react. Honestly, I was stuck Ms Green, I didn’t know what to do – whether to scream, or swear at them, or run. A few moments passed as the men continued rubbing themselves off. When I realized I was just standing there gawking at their insolent act, I abruptly looked around to suddenly notice how completely empty the street was. I turned towards the path and quickened my pace, almost sprinting to my apartment. The car kept up with me with the back door still open, while the two men sneered with filthy words roaring out of their mouths. I could have told you what they said but I was too scared to take notice of it. I spotted a couple of people at the small vendor a few steps in front of me, and as soon as I saw them, I ran towards them. Apparently the car driver registered their presence too, and he suddenly sped up. But before they left my side, I felt thick goo over my shirt, and my hair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bunch of guys at the vendor must have understood what happened looking at my sweaty and panting appearance, because they offered to walk me to my apartment, and I don’t quite remember what exactly I told them, but I most definitely appreciated the offer more than anything else at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home, in the mirror, I didn’t wish to look at myself. I took three showers that night and several others in the following days, as if the filth brewing within me could be washed off my skin. And I don’t have questions like “why would they do this, or what’s wrong with them,” because some people are just sick, and I know that. Sickness doesn’t need a reason but only a cause, and whatever the cause, it isn’t my concern. My concern, Ms Green, is why am I not able to let this go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been stuck in those few seconds. And despite possessing an extremely weak memory, I can recall each instant vividly, with the colors, the sound, and the smell, O the fucking smell steaming off that car and the semen in my hair, and the shrill of their laughter and the comments “bitch you’re hot” playing over and over again in my head as if something in it is broken, or as if some connection loose and it cannot seem to more further. I have lived that moment more than I have lived any other moment in my life, but I don’t know still how to exactly feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I obviously am angry, at the people who thought they could just do something like that to anybody, but surprisingly I am angry at myself more. I am angry that I didn’t react, or scream at them, or did not do a fucking thing, but just ran. I am angry at myself for getting stuck. With the way I have grown up, I am angry that I wasn’t prepared for anything like that. And to frustratingly add more, I am angry for feeling ashamed and disgusted at myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, Ms Green, do I feel embarrassed when nothing in any of it was my fault or doing. Do I have to be ashamed for being a girl, or worse, do I need to be ashamed for being a “hot bitch”? Why do I feel disgusted for owning skin, and body parts? Why can’t I seem to wash it off me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an act is done, intentionally or carelessly, for fun or with an intention to offend, planned or in the instant – the trauma and the string of questions that it brings with it afterwards is more haunting than the act itself. Whilst all minds are occupied with the offender and the possibilities of punishments that could justify, could we give perhaps a little more, if not equal, care to talk about the mental state of the victim sometime? Talking about it is a taboo and the general mentality believes than discussing it might further traumatize the offended, but can’t we see that not talking about it makes things worse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everyone would openly discuss and can freely call the wrong out to be wrong, and if we could acknowledge the natural thoughts to be natural, I might not feel so confused then. I would feel okay to be disgusted and angry and scared. I wouldn’t be so confused, and the blame the ones that are to be blamed. And not myself. But we don’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s why, Ms Green, I’d rather be in any other world than this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M&lt;/p&gt;

          </description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/letters/2020/06/06/letter-to-ms-green-1.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/letters/2020/06/06/letter-to-ms-green-1.html</guid>
          
          
          <category>letters</category>
          
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          
            <title>A Letter to Ms. Green</title>
          
          <author>mail@jayamishra.com (Jaya Mishra)</author>
          <description>
            &lt;p&gt;Dear Ms Green,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its been a while since we last spoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would shamelessly confess that I have missed you, although not as much as you would have wanted me to. I apologize for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been pretty busy. And sometimes when I get overwhelmed with emotions or situations, I often converse with you in my head, and at many such times I thought of sitting down and writing to you, but time didn’t forgive such moments to me. And now finally when it has, I am glad that it has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Green, how have you been? Have you been able to find answers to the questions we used to be puzzled over. I hope you’ll enlighten me too if any of those quests has been conquered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, something strange happened yesterday. I was dead tired, as usual, when the alarm struck, and although everything in my body had been screaming to get up, the will to leave the bed was just not there, and the excuse for an extra five minutes of sleep made me super late, to the point where I had only fifteen minutes at hand to reach the hospital. Taking the bus wasn’t an option, so I got one of those rent bikers to get me to the hospital so I could reach before the attendance for the day was barred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biker was an extremely polite man, in his thirties I guess, and when I told him I was late for duty, he took it too seriously. The zig-zag curves he started on were perhaps the most exciting and dangerous minutes I have experienced in my life. Now, I know that you must be judging my lifestyle based on the aforementioned statement, but Ms Green, I think you already know the kind of dull life I have always had and shall always be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, at one of the sharp turns that he made, our motorbike slid and almost lost balance, and a car running straight at a questionable speed at this early hour of the morning screeched to a sudden halt just inches from my knees. We could have lost balance, I could have fallen on the road, the car could have run over me, the motorbike or the tires of the car could have crushed my skull, they could have run over my legs, I could have been dragged on the road with my legs still stuck to the motorbike with my skin grazing the rough cemented road for miles, or maybe a million other crazily painful things could have happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My head, for the next ten minutes, or thirty, I am not really sure, was in a haze, in the possibility of what could have been. The entire morning, I kept on going back to the incidence, and thinking over and over again, what if I had died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ms Green, I am not afraid of death. Well, that’s not really correct, I am very much frightened of the idea of death, to suddenly not be one day, to suddenly cease to exist. Especially as a person who doesn’t believe in an afterlife, death does scare me. But when I say I am not afraid, what I actually mean is -  I get it. I accept it. The scary idea of not being able to finish everything, to suddenly disappear, to not be able to finish the whatever Netflix series I might would have started at the time, the idea of it – I accept it.
But in the moment, when I was almost there, in a moment what could have been the “it” moment, there was only one thought that scared me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People say that in the last moments of your life, you go through your whole life in a moment. All the memories – true or false ones, lived or imagined ones, all thoughts that were ever born in your head, all of them they cross through you in that one last moment. But the first thing that came to me, dear Ms Green, were words I had kept in my head, hidden, repeated, revised, learnt, but had never said to him. I regret that the most. To have not told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am still here, very much alive, making new memories and living the dull life, with those words repeating/rephrasing in my head every night, and every morning, and every time I see him, and every time I think of him, which is more frequent than any other thought; these words, they have become a living trauma. A wound I have been carrying with me which cannot heal as the only cure is to speak them loudly out to him, which won’t happen. I would not let it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you pity me, Ms Green, and I know that you wish me courage; I wish for it too. But I shall forever keep these words with me, with remorse, dying from them a thousand times. These words are sharp, and I shall forever choose to cut myself and forever bleed than to kill him with them. You know that I cannot say it, Ms Green, you have always known. And I know you wish as much as I do, that I could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dull life with burden of secrets of someone else’s mistakes, such life – I wish for it to conclude soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M&lt;/p&gt;

          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/letters/2020/06/05/letter-to-ms-green-1.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/letters/2020/06/05/letter-to-ms-green-1.html</guid>
          
          
          <category>letters</category>
          
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          
            <title>Soil</title>
          
          <author>mail@jayamishra.com (Jaya Mishra)</author>
          <description>
            &lt;p&gt;I and Him were so wrong for each other, but we could both never understand that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wished to mold me into a shape he seemed fit, and I was waiting forever for the day he might just come to like the original me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the soil and he was a cultivator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He uprooted every every plant that I let grow in me and had found beautiful, and he threw them away. He wished for a well maintained farm, and reap crops that he had dreamt of - and I nurtured them for him. He was a hard worker and he loved me, and he respected me, and he ruined me in his comprehension of saving me_.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each seed that fell into me, that I promised a life to, I let him kill- for the sake of faith in my love for him. And he pulled out each root, that he sought unnecessary and a waste, to save life in me. He stood proud at the sight of his beautiful farm before the harvest. His glittering eyes- both proud and thankful- at the sight of the full farm. He had successfully molded me in a way he had always wished to. I was happy for the happiness of my cultivator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years, a strange seed had fallen into my arms. It was a beautiful seed, I could imagine the pretty young plant sprouting out of it and turning into a majestic tree. And although I did not want to upset my cultivator, yet in the moment I made promises to the seed I was not sure to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am soil, and this is why I am, I am to provide life to it, this is my nature and this who I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I might love my cultivator as much as I want to, and wish to change myself for him as much as I want to, I cannot change the truth of my nature. I might fall in love with anybody but I would always be me, giving life to the seeds of desires and nurturing them to be a giant tree full of fruits of all of my desires. And my cultivator shall always prioritize his crops more than the wishes of the soil and her nature. The desires of each opposite to the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something did change this time. I tried and tried but I could not make this seed grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had lost my life, my capability of bearing plants. Years and years of commercial crops and poisonous fertilizers, I had lost my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cultivator looked at me with a broken heart as I lay barren. Although I was dear to him, we were not compatible anymore. I could not grow his crops anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cultivator was a grieving sculptor and I his clay. All this time he was molding me into something he thought he would love, but as the finished sculpture lay before his eyes, the sculptor couldn’t bear the sight of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fruitless, dead, and unproductive me- crying violently with guilt in my heart. Why could have I not loved the water instead? He would never make me cry. He would not have ruined me. Why could have I not fallen in love with the seed? We cannot live without each other. Why did I fall for my destroyer? And let him, willingly, ruin me, bit by bit, crying over my loss everytime he did and yet let him do it again? Is this what love is?&lt;/p&gt;

          </description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
          <link>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2020/05/17/soil.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/thoughts/2020/05/17/soil.html</guid>
          
          
          <category>thoughts</category>
          
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
